Jacob Liberman

jacobliberman@gmail.com

Austin, TX

Summary

Product manager with a background in open source software, cloud computing, data analysis, and high performance computing (HPC). Extensive experience working with the US Federal Government and in LATAM. Multiple industry and academic publications. Frequent presenter at technology conferences. Ability to context switch between C-level strategic planning and engineering-level technical discussions.

Experience

Senior Principal Product Manager, Emerging Technology

Red Hat, May 2018 - Present

• Field product manager with cross organizational, cross product impact. OpenShift and OpenStack integration lead. HPC and cloud convergence, accelerators. Technology evangelism through conference presentations and publications.

Principal Product Manager, Cloud, Virtualization, Containers

Red Hat, November 2016 - May 2018

• Feature planning and implementation, bug identification and fix. Represented strategic customers to cloud business unit. Cloud computing infrastructure design and implementation. Field enablement through hackfest planning and execution.

Principal Software Engineer, Cloud Computing

Red Hat, January 2012 - November 2016

• Developed, tested, and published cloud computing reference architectures based on Red Hat OpenStack Platform, Enterprise Linux, and Hadoop.

Rugby 7s Head Coach

University of Texas at Austin, August 2010 - July 2015

• Founder and coach of University of Texas Rugby 7s team. Ranked #20 2011, #13 2012, #12 2013 out of more than 500 college rugby programs.

Performance analyst

Philippine Rugby Football Union, June 2013 – August 2013

• National team performance analyst during the 2013 Rugby 7s World Cup in Moscow, Russia. Video capture, coding, statistical analysis, and scouting.

Performance Engineer, Scientific and Cloud Computing

Advanced Micro Devices, November 2009 – January 2012

• Designed and conducted server performance studies for competitive analysis. Helped customers

improve the performance of their codes on our systems. Managed lab clusters for remote customer evaluation. Traveled to customer sites to conduct benchmarks for acceptance testing.

Development Engineer, High Performance Computing

Dell, August 2006 - November 2009

• Lead performance engineer. Conducted server performance studies using standard benchmarks and applications. Shared results via publications and presentations. Evaluated storage, networking, and software technologies for inclusion in our product.

Curriculum Designer/Subject Matter Expert

Dell, February 2005 - August 2006

• Developed classroom and online technical curriculum for the field consulting team. High Performance Computing (HPC) subject matter expert.

Services Consulting Engineer

Dell, April 1999 - February 2005

• Remote field services and support engineer. I helped customers deploy EMC storage arrays and attach UNIX and Linux servers to them.

Education

Texas State University

Master's Program, Computer Science

- In progress, 30 hours upper division coursework
- Researching CUDA acceleration for computational model of human eye movement,

The University of Texas at Austin

Master's Degree, Technology in Education

- 4.0 GPA with course work in learning theory, statistics, and scientific computing.

University of Wisconsin-Madison

Bachelor's Degree, English Literature

- Creative writing emphasis

Volunteer Service

Board member

Trojans Pop Warner, August 2015 – 2017

Web services and American football tackle saftey coach.

Board Member — Texas Rugby Alumni Network

Texas Exes, May 2015 - Present

Organize alumni events, recruit members, and manage an endowed scholarship fund.

Awards

- Red Hat Portfolio Marketing Customer Impact Award, 2018
- Red Hat Summit Best presenter award, 2017
- Red Hat Summit Best presenter award, 2016

Selected Publications, Example Code

https://github.com/jliberma